Joon Y. Lee

400 Riverfront Boulevard #323, Elmwood Park, NJ 07407 • (201) 937 – 6929 • joonyoung82@gmail.com https://joonyoung82.github.io/

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Software Quality Assurance Engineer with over 11 years of professional experience in mobile technology industry. Proven track record of successful software releases and management with over 25 smartphones for all four major carriers with more than twenty million units sold and experience working on mobile application with over 2 billion users. Key achievements include leading software quality assurance team on releasing HTC One M7 and M8 both of which were awarded "Smartphone of the year" at the Mobile World Congress in 2013 and 2014.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Facebook, Inc.

New York, NY

Quality Assurance Analyst II

April 2018 - Current

- Run software quality test for iOS and Android apps for Local Discovery team to catch bugs, offer design feedback, and measure performance.
- Work with Product Managers, Software Engineers, Product Specialist, and Engineering Managers to enhance software quality and capabilities.
- Serve as a mini-lead as lone QA representative in NY to be the channel between 3rd party test team in India and QA managers in SF.
- Develop testing plans, strategies, cases, scenarios for each new feature and assign to testers overseas.
- Log test results into testing database, manage the life cycle of the bugs, compile weekly status, properly prioritize work flow and bug fix needs and communicate results with the team.

HTC America, Inc.

Bedminster, NJ

Principal Software Quality Engineer

April 2017 – Feb 2018

- Managed development and execution of software test plans to identify software problems and their causes.
- Performed black-box tests, system software tests, and radio stability tests on all pre-launched mobile phones to ensure software and hardware quality and functionality on all devices released to Verizon and Sprint carriers.
- Coached and developed QA engineers by sharing knowledge on test plans and carrier guidelines.
- Ensured software quality throughout the life cycle of the device from pre-launch, regression, maintenance release, and OS update via FOTA.
- Conducted weekly meetings with key stakeholders in U.S. headquarters to discuss project progress, escalations, timeline, and determine appropriate next steps.
- Collaborated with PM, TAM, and R&D teams to drive projects to deliver quality SW on time.
- Initiated meetings with vendors to reduce results discrepancy in DoU test and successfully decreased retest occurrences down to 50%.
- Led quality assurance efforts for camera, third-party applications, display, RF, and audio on all projects including Google Pixel2, which ranked highest in smartphone camera on DxOMark at launch.

Senior Software Quality Engineer

May 2015 – *April* 2017

- Performed black-box software testing on smartphones, tablets, wearables, and accessories.
- Led SWQA efforts in collaboration project with Google to build their first smartphone; Pixel and Pixel XL.
- Implemented Automated Test System hardware that can be controlled remotely by R&D in Taiwan, which improved the testing and reporting process cycle by significantly reducing the test duration by 70%.
- Performed carrier test plans at Verizon lab: WiFi Aggregation, Carrier Aggregation, Days of Usage, eMBMS.
- Executed manual test plans for software quality according to carrier requirements: VoLTE, iRAT, Passpoint.
- Exceeded the target rate of 95% of closing issues on software defects before lab submission for all devices launched.

Project Manager – User Trial Division

May 2014 - May 2015

- Managed user trials to ensure software was ready and stable for launch.
- Managed issues and feedbacks found in user trial by collecting, triaging, and verifying fixes.
- Drove effective closure rate of 95% on issues reported through user trials by validating issue symptoms, following up with participants to record the appropriate evidence and reproducing & recording issues as needed.
- Worked closely with PM, TAM, and R&D to solve user pain points to improve overall customer experience.

- Performed system software and radio field test to verify device software stability and functionality.
- Performed automated tests by modifying and running scripts in LUA for software and hardware quality on system stability, battery life, and network interoperability on Android and Windows devices.
- Collected and analyzed logs from the automated tests and managed technical reports to R&D.
- Performed field test for RF stability and readiness for preFIT, FIT, VZ Navi test, VZW GPS test.
- GSM/UMTS network test for AT&T and T-Mobile: 10776, 15595 stress test, data throughput test, etc.
- Executed manual test plans for software quality according to carrier requirements: VZW GPS Test, SMS/EMS Test, Full Regression Test, Location Based System, Verizon P1, etc.

LG Electronics MobileComm U.S.A., Inc.

Morristown, NJ

Software Verification Engineer

Jan 2008 - May 2011

- Developed and executed software test plans in order to identify software problems and their causes.
- Performed gray-box and black-box software testing on all pre-launched mobile phones.
- Analyzed carrier requirements and developed test plans, test scenarios, and test cases.
- Reported and tracked bugs, replicated reported bugs, verified bug fixes and new functionalities, regression test new SW releases, support R&D by submitting appropriate logs.
- Tested capability of the device to update Firmware Over the Air.
- Prepared technical reports of software defects and error analysis along with the logs.
- Managed software quality on Android, Windows OS, BREW OS, bluetooth headsets, wireless charging pad, car-kits, USB modem and more.
- Successfully submitted over 20 stable mobile softwares to Verizon.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Tools: QXDM, QPST, ADB, Fastboot, HP Quality Center, Monsoon Power Monitor, MTTY, Joyphone,

DDMS, Testmode, Atlantis Logger, Quip, Adobe Photoshop, MS Office

• Languages: Python, Javascript, Git, LUA, HTML, CSS

• Fluent in: English, Korean

EDUCATION

New Jersey Institute of Technology – College of Engineering Bachelor of Science in Industrial Engineering Newark, NJ May 2007

VOLUNTEER

Organized Fundraisers

2014 - 2018

- 5K Run, Flag Football Tournament, Service Auction
- Led/participated in organizing three fundraisers which raised over \$10k in total for orphanages in Korea, Thailand, and Nicaragua for food & water, education, and housing.

Overseas & Domestic Missions

2005 - 2017

- Thailand, Central Asia, Far East, Haiti, Jordan, Harlem, Lynn
- Served the underserved communities, refugee camps, children's home, and local churches by supporting them with food & water, aid, education, counseling, bible studies and spending time with the locals.
- Led three mission teams to Lynn, MA, which supported Cambodian refugees who were victims of the Killing fields by providing education, housing, and counseling.

Student President at Korea Campus Crusades for Christ. East Coast Chapter

2007

- Led as president consisting of 10 NYC college campuses with over 2,000 members.
- Organized weekly worships, annual conferences, and overseas missions.